RAFFAELE VALENTI

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - PROTECTED CATEGORIES (L. 68/99)

Contacts



+39 348 469 1962



raffaele-valenti@protonmail.com



raffaelevalenti.it/



github.com/raffitheo



linkedin.com/in/raffaele-valenti/

Programming

JavaScript	
TypeScript	Advanced
Web (HTML, CSS	Advanced S/SAS Suite/LESS)
C#	Advanced
Java	Advanced
C/C++	Intermediate
Python	Beginner
	Beginner

Skills focus

Dart (Flutter)

3D Modeling: Good knowledge of **Hard Surface** modeling with **Blender** and the use of slicing software for 3D printing preparation.

2D Design and Texturing: Good knowledge of GIMP and Inkscape for 2D graphics, as well as Substance Painter and Substance Designer for creating and managing advanced textures.

Game Engines: In-depth knowledge of Unity and basic skills in using Unreal Engine.

Front-end: Extensive experience with React, React Native, and Ionic, along with a good knowledge of other frameworks and libraries such as Angular and Vue.

Work experience

2024-11 present

Software Developer

Tecnolife IT Consulting S.r.l. - Remote, Trieste

Design and front-end development of React applications.

Skills acquired: Development of **Flutter** applications, including the use of tools such as **FlutterFlow**; bases for programming in **Python**, utilizing **Docker** containers for managing and deploying the various environments needed by the application (development, quality assurance and production).

2024-10 2024-03

Digital Transformation Analyst

FINCANTIERI S.p.A. - Hybrid, Trieste

 Design and development of back-end and front-end libraries to better and more simply manage future updates of various applications.
 In particular, the front-end libraries were created using React and Storybook for the visualization and documentation of graphic components.

Skills acquired: Creation and utilization of internal front-end and back-end libraries, with a focus on maintenance, versioning, compatibility, and developer experience.

2024-03 2021-11

Digital Transformation Analyst (Apprenticeship)

FINCANTIERI S.p.A. - Hybrid, Trieste

- Design and implementation of a complex technology stack, comprising both a back-end and a front-end. Both have their respective environments (development and production) and dedicated release pipelines.
 The solutions were built using React for the front-end and .NET 6/8 with Entity Framework for the back-end.
- Full-stack design and development of web applications in a SharePoint Online environment using the technology stack designed.

Skills acquired: Coordination of a development team consisting of 2 to 4 members, software maintenance with a focus on bug fixing and implementation of change requests, execution of user acceptance testing (UAT), and management of the relationship with end users.

2021-10 2021-04

Beginner

Digital Transformation Analyst (Internship)

FINCANTIERI S.p.A. - Hybrid, Trieste

- Front-end design and development of web applications without a back-end in a SharePoint Online environment.
 - The solutions were built using React, Bootstrap, and jQuery.
- Development of an augmented reality application for shipyards, designed for 3D visualization of ship assembly plans on Android devices.
 The app was built using the **Unity** game engine, leveraging its AR technologies and features.

Skills acquired: Operational management on behalf of a large company in the IT sector, with a focus on meeting deadlines, planning deliveries, and releasing software in production environments.

2019-07 2019-01

Android and Web Developer (Internship)

CodaQ S.r.I.s. - In office, Area Science Park (Padriciano, Trieste)

- Development of an Android application integrated with a pre-existing queue management system.
 - The app features a dynamic user interface that can be modified in real time without the need for code recompilation.
- Development of a mobile application for Android and iOS devices, aimed at managing patient access flows at the IRCCS Materno Infantile "Burlo Garofolo".

The application was built using the **Angular** framework and **NativeScript** libraries to ensure cross-platform compatibility.

Skills acquired: Management of an IT company, coordination of software projects, and effective collaboration within development teams involving multiple programmers working on the same project.

RAFFAELE VALENTI

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - PROTECTED CATEGORIES (L. 68/99)

Technical skills

Software: Microsoft Windows, Linux (Ubuntu Desktop, Ubuntu Server, PopOS, Tumbleweed), Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, Cursor, Trae, Eclipse, Unity, Blender, GIMP, Inkscape Libraries and Frameworks: .NET, Entity Framework, Node.js, React, React Native, Ionic, Expo, Vite, Webpack

Version Control: Git, GitHub Desktop, Sourcetree, GitHub, GitLab, Bitbucket, Azure DevOps **Databases:** MongoDB, SQL Server Management Studio, PostgreSQL, Firebase, Supabase **Others:** Coding Als, Azure, Docker, Rancher Desktop, FlutterFlow

Educational background

2019-07 2017-10 Higher Technician for the Development and Management of Biomedical IT Solutions (TIB)

Fondazione Istituto Tecnico Superiore "Alessandro Volta"

2017-07 2012-09 High school diploma in Chemistry, Materials, and Biotechnology

Istituto Tecnico Statale "Grazia Deledda - Max Fabiani"

Notes

Recognition under Law 68/99: 74% disability and inclusion in the protected categories pursuant to Law 68/99 (Italy).

Privacy

I authorize the processing of personal data in compliance with the applicable data protection laws, in particular, the European General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) 2016/679, Legislative Decree 30/06/2003 no. 196 and subsequent amendments and integrations.

Back-end: Strong knowledge of C#, JavaScript, and TypeScript, enabling me to work with various back-end technologies, including Entity Framework (for C#) or Express (for JavaScript and TypeScript).

Languages

Mothertongue (C2)
French

Mothertongue (C2)
English

Advanced (B2)